Kai Geffen

Phone: 413-409-2927

Location: New York City

Email: GeffenKai@Gmail.com

GitHub: KaiGeffen **Website:** kaigeffen.com

Senior Software Engineer

Versatile and determined software engineer with 6 years of client and industry experience. Engaged community member and builder in the Zero-Knowledge space. Brings years of experience in managing, facilitating, and communicating with clients and peers to achieve excellence in software solutions. Passionate math and problem-solver who holds the value and viability of the product in mind at all times.

Professional Experience

June 2023 -December 2023

Senior Software Engineer, CTO

IronMill

- Lead the team in designing high-level scope for our project, creating diagrams and specifications, breaking it down into actionable tasks, and supporting best-practices are used throughout
- Attended industry-leading conferences and worked with key investors and partners to refine product-market fit
- Researched and advised on the technical aspects of Zero-Knowledge
 Proofs and where they could deliver the most value to our audience
- Executed end-to-end development in both Python and Typescript for both frontend and backend

Winter 2023 - June 2023

Zero-Knowledge Exploration

Independent Exploration

- Researched Zero-Knowledge Proofs and verifiable execution
- Attended ZK Libson, implemented Tip5 hash function in Miden assembly for a hackathon project
- Contributed to RISC Zero's version 0.14.0 release

Summer 2020 -Winter 2022 **Software Engineer**

CelestialTCG.com - Boston, MA

- Designed, built, and host a web-app game using Typescript for client-side code, Python for server-side, and Postgres for user database
- Used Websockets for connecting to the server, OAuth for account management, Git for version-control, DigitalOcean for cloud hosting, and Canvas for frontend visuals
- Hired and managed a 4 person team working to develop the art, user-interface, and sound experience for the game

Education

Summer 2017	Master's of Science in Computer Science (Incomplete) University of Massachusetts Amherst (Privacy and Security focus)
Fall 2016	Bachelor of Science in Computer Science University of Massachusetts Amherst (3.77 Major GPA)
Spring 2012	Associate of Science in Mechanical Engineering Greenfield Community College (3.93 Overall GPA)

Areas of Expertise

 Typescript 	 Zero-Knowledge 	• Ruby	 Figma
Python	 OCaml 	• Git	 Docker

Other Roles and Achievements

Tutored math: Hundreds of hours of experience working with more than 10 clients over a 10 year period. Many clients returned and demonstrated improved results and understanding.

SomAlive Audio Software: Collaborated and advised client on successfully designing, executing, and testing a custom audio processing application over a year long contract. Developed user experience, low-level audio processing, and device configuration in Python.

Internship at Atalasoft: Extensively tested new features and updates to the company's image processing SDK. Wrote and facilitated the use of a C# program which automatically merged source code comments with the online documentation for the entire SDK.